Guide to the Fredericka Martin Papers ALBA.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Medical Personnel: Biographical Files and Correspondence, 1936-1988; 83177
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Clippings, 1937-1939, 1944, 1988; 83371 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Correspondence from Paris and Spain, Oct 1937-Sep 1938; 83370 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Correspondence, undated, 1968-1969; 83369 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Correspondence, 1970-1979; 83368 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Correspondence, 1980-1984; 83367 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Passenger List ("Veendam"), Sep 3, 1938; 83366 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Questionnaires, 1938, 1968; 83365 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - United States: Grunsky, Eugenia: Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1939, 1969; 83364 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - United States: Guzman, Jaime de, 1937-1940, 1970-1975; 83363 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - United States: Harris Marantz, Ray: Correspondence from Spain, Mar 1938-Dec 1938; 83362 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - United States: Harris Marantz, Ray: Correspondence, 1967-1988; 83361 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - United States: Harris Marantz, Ray: Questionnaire and Writings, undated, 1970; 83360 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - United States: Harris Marantz, Ray: Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938; 83359 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - United States: Hartmann, Hermine: Correspondence, undated, 1969-1979; 83358 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - United States: Hartmann, Hermine: Correspondence, 1980-1986; 83357 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - United States: Hartmann, Hermine: Correspondence from Hospital Frederica Montceny (Murcia), 1937; 83356 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - United States: Hartmann, Hermine: Questionnaire, Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938, 1969-1970; 83355 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - United States: Hartzman, Jack (Ambulance Driver), undated; 83354 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - United States: Harvan, Rose, undated, 1937-1941, 1968-1977; 83353 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - United States: Hayes, Thomas (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1937-1938, 1975; 83352 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - United States: Henderson, Florence Elizabeth (Bessie), 1937-1938, 1968-1975; 83351 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - United States: Henderson, Florence Elizabeth (Bessie): Passenger List and Menu ("Veendam"), Nov 7, 1937; 83350 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - United States: Hene, Julius, undated, 1937, 1970; 83349 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - United States: Hernaiz, Dulce Corona, undated, 1937-1938, 1969-1975; 83348 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - United States: Hershkowitz, Hannah (Honey), undated, 1937-1938, 1970-1977; 83347 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - United States: Highkin, Joseph, 1937-1938, 1968-1970; 83346 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - United States: Hilkevitch, Aaron, 1937-1938, 1968-1980; 83345 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - United States: Hirschfield, Victor (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1937-1939; 83344 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - United States: Hutchins, Evelyn (a.k.a. Evelyn Rahman): Correspondence, 1967-1982; 83343 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - United States: Hutchins, Evelyn (a.k.a. Evelyn Rahman): Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938, 1968-1970; 83342 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - United States: Jacquier, Ives, undated, 1937-1938, 1970-1971; 83341 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - United States: Jankovic, Matylde, 1937-1938, 1968-1980; 83340 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - United States: Jensky, Toby: Correspondence, undated; 83339 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - United States: Jensky, Toby: Correspondence, 1940-1959; 83338 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - United States: Jensky, Toby: Correspondence, 1960-1979; 83337 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - United States: Jensky, Toby: Correspondence, 1980-1984; 83336 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - United States: Jensky, Toby: Correspondence: Spanish Civil War (typed manuscript with annotations), 1937-1938; 83335 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - United States: Jensky, Toby: Questionnaire, Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938, 1970-1974; 83334 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - United States: Kahn, Sally, undated, 1937-1939, 1970-1971; 83333 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - United States: Kee, Salaria (a.k.a. Salaria Kea): Ambulance Tour: Report and Itineraries (photocopies and originals), 1938; 83332 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - United States: Kee, Salaria (a.k.a. Salaria Kea): Articles and Clippings, 1937-1938, 1977-1987; 83331 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - United States: Kee, Salaria (a.k.a. Salaria Kea): Correspondence, ca.1938; 83330 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - United States: Kee, Salaria (a.k.a. Salaria Kea): Correspondence, 1968-1984; 83329 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - United States: Kee, Salaria (a.k.a. Salaria Kea): Leaflet, 1938; 83328 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - United States: Kee, Salaria (a.k.a. Salaria Kea): Pamphlet: "A Negro Nurse in Republican Spain" (Reprint of 1938 publication), 1977; 83327 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - United States: Kee, Salaria (a.k.a. Salaria Kea): Memoirs (typescript), undated; 83326 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - United States: Kee, Salaria (a.k.a. Salaria Kea): Questionnaire, Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938, 1968-1977; 83325 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - United States: Kipness, Bertha, 1938, 1968-1970; 83324 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - United States: Klein, Jack: Correspondence, undated, 1975-1977; 83323 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - United States: Klein, Jack: Dental Patient Record (photocopy), May 1938-Sep 1938; 83322 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - United States: Klein, Jack: Questionnaire, Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938, 1970; 83321 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - United States: Kornblum, Morris (a.k.a. Morris Balter): Questionnaire, Passport, Research Notes and Photocopies, 1937-1938, 1970-1980; 83320 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - United States: Kornell, Irving, undated, 1937-1938, 1972-1977; 83319 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - United States: Kraus, Martin (Mac) (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1979-1981; 83318 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - United States: Larsen, Leonard, 1937-1938, 1968-1972; 83317 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - United States: Leight, Clara, 1968-1984; 83316 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - United States: Levine, Jacob (Driver), undated, 1938-1979; 83315 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - United States: Levine, Mabel Fay and Meyer, 1970-1971; 83314 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - United States: Levine, May: Questionnaire, Research Notes and Photocopies, 1937, 1968-1978; 83313 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - United States: Lopez, Epiphanio, undated, 1937-1938, 1975; 83312 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - United States: Malbin, Barney: Correspondence from Spain (typed transcriptions), 1937-1938, 1971; 83310 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - United States: Malbin, Barney: Correspondence and Photocopies from Virginia Malbin, 1937, 1970-1977; 83311 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - United States: Malbin, Barney: Questionnaire, Writings, Research Notes, and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1940; 83309 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - United States: Miller, Carol M., 1937, 1969-1971; 83299 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - United States: Margolis, Grace, 1937-1938, 1968-1975; 83308 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Biographical material (General), Personal Documents, Notes (some from Spain)and Reminiscences (fragments), undated, 1935-1938, 1981; 83307 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Diaries/Date Books, 1949; 83304 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Diaries/Date Books, 1963; 83303 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Diaries/Date Books, 1966-1970; 83305 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Diaries/Date Books, 1973, 1975; 452444 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Diaries/Date Books, 1976-1979; 83302 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Diaries/Date Books, 1977; 452445 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Diaries/Date Books, 1981-1982; 83306 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Diaries/Date Books, 1983; 83301 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Diaries/Date Books, 1988(?); 452477 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Diaries/Date Books, 1989; 452478 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Diaries/Date Books (loose pages and notes), 1970s; 452479 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Memoir of 1972 Return to Spain (draft), 452481 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - United States: Martin, Fredericka: Spanish Civil War Hospital Ward Journal, Feb 1937-Jul 1937; 452482 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - United States: Merims, Sonia, 1937-1938, 1968-1985; 83300 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - United States: Mitchell, Martha, 1937-1938, 1969-1978; 83298 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - United States: Morrell, William (Driver), undated, 1971; 83297 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - United States: Moser, George: Spanish Civil War: Postcard and Clippings, 1937; 83296 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - United States: Moser, George: Correspondence, Research Notes and Photocopies, 1937-1938, 1969-1983; 83295 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - United States: Neugass, James (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1938, 1968; 83294 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - United States: Novac Ryan, Alba: Correspondence, undated, 1963-1964; 83293 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - United States: Novac Ryan, Alba: Correspondence, 1971; 83292 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - United States: Novac Ryan, Alba: Correspondence, 1972; 83291 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - United States: Novac Ryan, Alba: Correspondence, 1973; 83290 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - United States: Novac Ryan, Alba: Correspondence, 1975-1979; 83289 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - United States: Novac Ryan, Alba: Death, 1979-1980; 83288 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - United States: Novac Ryan, Alba: Research, Correspondence, Notes, and Questionnaire, undated, 1938, 1968-1976; 83287 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - United States: Novac, Ryan: Spanish Civil War Recollections, 1971-1972; 83286 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - United States: Novac Ryan: William Ryan, Writings and HUAC Hearings, undated, 1940-1944, 1971; 83285 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - United States: Palmer, Lillian (fiche medicale), 1937; 454205 (Box 1, Folder 27A)
  - United States: Penrod, John Arthur (Ambulance Driver), 1980; 83284 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - United States: Perez, Aurelio (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1938-1939, 1968-1984; 83283 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - United States: Pike, William: Correspondence, undated, 1968-1984; 83282 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - United States: Pike, William: Questionnaire and Research Materials, undated, 1937-1938, 1969-1971; 83281 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - United States: Pitts, Donald: Correspondence, Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938, 1968-1977; 83280 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - United States: Platkin Torrance, Mary Louise: Correspondence and Notes, undated, 1968-1982; 83279 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - United States: Platkin Torrance, Mary Louise: Spanish Civil War Diary (photocopy), 1937-1946; 83278 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - United States: Posner, John Jacob: Correspondence and Research Notes, undated, 1968-1975; 83277 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - United States: Posner, John Jacob: Research Photocopies: Articles and Correspondence, 1937-1942; 83276 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - United States: Purviance, Carlton C. and Katherine, 1937-1938, 1968-1969; 83275 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - United States: Queignac, Pierre (Driver), undated; 83274 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - United States: Quiñones, Gabriel Jack (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1938, 1971-1974; 83273 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - United States: Rackley Simon, Mildred: Correspondence, undated, 1968-1986; 83272 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - United States: Rackley Simon, Mildred: Questionnaires, undated, 1971, 1976; 83271 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - United States: Rackley Simon, Mildred: Research Notes and Photocopies, 1937-1938, 1968-1976; 83270 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - United States: Rackley Simon, Mildred: Spanish Civil War Memoirs (incomplete typescriptand FM queries), undated; 83269 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - United States: Rader, Mary, 1936-1939, 1967-1976; 83268 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - United States: Rahman, Carl (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1937-1939, 1967-1978; 83267 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - United States: Rintz, Norman: Correspondence and Questionnaires, 1969-1979; 83266 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - United States: Rintz, Norman: Interview, Research Notes and Photocopies, 1937-1938, 1969-1976; 83265 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - United States: Robbins, Seymour Stanley, undated, 1975-1976; 83264 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - United States: Roberts, Hilda Bell: "Brightest Room" (photocopy typescript of Spanish Civil War memoirs), 1952; 83263 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - United States: Roberts, Hilda Bell: Correspondence, 1968-1982; 83262 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - United States: Roberts, Hilda Bell: Questionnaire, 1970; 83261 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - United States: Roberts, Hilda Bell: Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1939; 83260 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - United States: Romer, Edna and Sam, undated, 1936-1938, 1969-1977; 83259 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - United States: Samuel, Karl, 1936, 1970; 83258 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - United States: Schiff, Sam, 1970-1972; 83257 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - United States: Schulman, Rebecca: Correspondence, 1938; 83256 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - United States: Schulman, Rebecca: Correspondence, undated, 1968-1984; 83255 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - United States: Schulman, Rebecca: Questionnaires, 1937, circa 1970; 83254 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - United States: Schulman, Rebecca: Research Notes and Photocopies, 1937-1938, 1971-1974; 83253 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - United States: Seborer, Celia Greenspan: Correspondence (photocopies), 1937; 83252 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - United States: Seborer, Celia Greenspan: Correspondence and Notes, 1953, 1968-1984; 83251 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - United States: Seborer, Celia Greenspan: Questionnaire, 1971; 83250 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - United States: Shuldiner, Ann: Questionnaire, Correspondence, Research Notes, undated, 1970-1971; 83249 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - United States: Silverstein, Esther: Correspondence and Research Notes, 1937, 1968-1980; 83248 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - United States: Silverstein, Esther: Questionnaire, ca.1970; 83247 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - United States: Simon, John L.: Correspondence, 1968-1986; 83246 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - United States: Simon, John L.: Questionnaire and Research Materials, undated, 1938, 1969-1970; 83245 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - United States: Sorrell, Allan H.: Correspondence, undated, 1937-1938, 1966-1977; 83244 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - United States: Sorrell, Allan H.: Diary (photocopied typescript), Feb 1937; 83243 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - United States: Stadt, Zachary M.: Questionnaire, Correspondence, Research Notes and Photocopies, 1937-1938, 1970-1980; 83242 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - United States: Straus, Mark: Correspondence, Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1938, 1969-1981; 83241 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Clippings, 1937-1938, 1948, 1963-1969; 83240 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, undated; 83239 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, 1937, 1942-1959; 83238 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, 1960-1965; 83237 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, 1966-1967; 83236 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, Jan 1968-Jun 1968; 83235 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, Jul 1968-Dec 1968; 83234 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, 1969; 83233 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, Jan 1970-Mar 1970; 83232 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, Apr 1970-May 1970; 452278 (Box 12, Folder 12A)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, Jun 1970-Aug 1970; 452285
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, Sep 1970-Dec 1970; 83231 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, 1971; 83230 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, 1972-1975; 83229 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, 1976-1979; 83228 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence, 1980-1982; 83227 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Correspondence: Landis, Arthur, 1964; 83226 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Nurses License, 1934-1935; 83225 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Postcards and Telegrams from Spain (photocopies), 1937-1938; 83224 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1938-1939, 1970-1974; 83223 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Spanish Civil War Diary (photocopy), 1937; 83222 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - United States: Taft, Anne: Teruel: Notes, undated, 1970-1971; 83221 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - United States: Taini, Wayne J. (Ambulance Driver), undated, 1938-1939, 1970; 83220 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - United States: Temple, Leonora: Correspondence, undated, 1971-1978; 83219 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - United States: Temple, Leonora: Correspondence, 1979-1987; 83218 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - United States: Temple, Leonora: Passport, 1937; 83217 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - United States: Temple, Leonora: Questionnaire, undated; 83216 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - United States: Temple, Leonora: Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938, 1969-1972; 83215 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - United States: Temple, Leonora: Valencia Arrest, 1938, 1977; 83214 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - United States: Tiship, Victor, 1936, 1970; 83213 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - United States: Towsen, Augustus N. (Gus): Correspondence, undated, 1946-1955, 1968-1969; 83212 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - United States: Towsen, Augustus N. (Gus): Correspondence, 1970-1972; 83211 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - United States: Towsen, Augustus N. (Gus): Correspondence, 1973-1976; 83210 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - United States: Towsen, Augustus N. (Gus): Correspondence, 1977-1983; 83209 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - United States: Towsen, Augustus N. (Gus): Research Notes and Clippings, undated, 1969-1979; 83208 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - United States: Towsen, Augustus N. (Gus): Spain: Correspondence and Clipping, 1938; 83207 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - United States: Towsen, Augustus N. (Gus): Writings, undated, 1967-1970; 83206 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - United States: Towsen, Augustus N. (Gus): Writings: Poetry, undated, 1967-1978; 83205 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - United States: Towsen, Augustus N. (Gus): Writings: Poetry: "Ballad of Teruel", 1972; 83204 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - United States: Vanzant, Frances R.: Clippings, 1926-1938; 83203 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - United States: Vanzant, Frances R.: Correspondence from Spain (photocopies), 1937-1938; 83202 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - United States: Vanzant, Frances R.: Correspondence (Inquiries and Responses), 1969-1972; 83201 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - United States: Vanzant, Frances R.: Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938; 83200 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - United States: Vogel, Sidney: Correspondence, Research, Notes and Photocopies, 1936-1938, 1969-1976; 83199 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - United States: Wacksman, Rose: Correspondence, Research Notes and Photocopies, 1937-1939, 1968-1979; 83198 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - United States: Wagonon, Alice Elizabeth: Correspondence, 1968-1988; 83197 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - United States: Wagnon: Alice Elizabeth: Correspondence: from French Refugee Camp, 1939; 83196 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - United States: Wagnon, Alice Elizabeth: Questionnaire and Recollections, 1971; 83195 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - United States: Wagnon, Alice Elizabeth: Research Notes, Clippings and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938, 1971; 83194 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - United States: Wagnon, Alice Elizabeth: Salvoconducto/Safe Conduct Passes and Ephemera, 1938; 83193 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - United States: Weiner, Rose: Correspondence and Questionnaire, 1969-1975; 83192 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - United States: Weiner, Rose: Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1939, 1969-1971; 83191 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - United States: Weisfield, Edwin S., undated, 1937-1938, 1969-1972; 83190 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - United States: Weissman, Helene: Correspondence, undated, 1966-1982; 83189 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - United States: Weissman, Helene: Questionnaire, Research Notes and Photocopies, 1937, 1968-1970; 83188 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - United States: Weissman, Oscar Israel, 1969-1979; 83187 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - United States: White, Leigh, 1938, 1943, 1968; 83186 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - United States: Wilkes, Harry: Inquiries, Research Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1937-1938, 1977-1983; 83185 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - United States: Williams, Helen: Research Correspondence, Notes and Photocopies, 1938, 1968-1970; 83184 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - United States: Zauderer, Louis J.: Inquiries, Research Notes and Photocopies, 1937-1938, 1968-1977; 83183 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - United States: Zlatovski, George (a.k.a. George Michaels): Research Notes and Photocopies, 1938, 1957; 83182 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Yugoslavia: Doctors, undated, 1972-1975; 83181 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Yugoslavia: Nurses and Medical Students, undated, 1971-1975; 83180 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Yugoslavia: Bechman, Elizabeth (a.k.a. Elizabeth Gavric), 1972; 83179 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Yugoslavia: Dragutin, Fodor (a.k.a. Theodore Balk), 1972; 83178 (Box 13, Folder 43)
- Series II: Medical Subject Files, 1937-1987; 83036
  Series II. Medical Subject Files, 1937-1984. This series contains Martin's research files pertaining to medical aid and services in Spain during the war. Materials related to the Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy are located in this series including research correspondence related to the establishment and structure of the Medical Bureau; brochures, press releases, leaflets, and other ephemera; information on the merger with the North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy; and documents related to the passport application policy for Medical Bureau personnel. A file of correspondence, notes and written statements offers evidence of Martin's dogged efforts to amass and safeguard materials documenting the history of the Medical Bureau. The bulk of this series is devoted to files on the dozens of medical sites that were established by the International Brigade medical units during the war. Included are accounts excerpted by Martin from letters written by medical and combat volunteers detailing conditions and staffing, notes, clippings, and printed material related to each location.
  There are several research files on the International Brigades medical services, as well as information on ambulance donations and ambulance drivers. Photocopies of articles from Ayuda Medica Internacional, the organ of the IB medical services, and files on treatment including the utilization of Hiram Orr's closed cast system can also be found here. Noteworthy is a hand-drawn diagram of a medical facility, circa 1937, headed "Sanitary Service of a Battalion in the Spanish Republican Army."
  - Ambulance Drivers and Chauffeurs, undated, 1968-1970, 1975; 83176 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Ambulance Drivers: Evacuation Group #1, undated, 1938, 1972; 83175 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Ambulance Unit: American Consulate General Memoranda (photocopies), 1936-1937; 83174 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Ambulances: Donations, undated, 1936-1938; 83173 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Ambulances: Ernest Hemingway Donation (copies of EH correspondence with Roger Chase), 1937; 454635 (Box 14, Folder 4A)
  - Ambulances: Scottish Unit, undated, 1936-1939; 83172 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Ayuda Medica Internacional(photocopied clippings and notes), 1938; 83171 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Centrale Sanitaire Internationale d'Aide a l'Espagne (CSI): Accounts for Returning Personnel, 1937-1938; 454630 (Box 14, Folder 6A)
  - Food and Sanitation, undated, 1937-1938, 1969-1971; 83170 (Box 14, Folder 7)